Tor Francis

Philadelphia, PA | 678-790-2697 | torfrancis447@gmail.com linkedin.com/tor-francis | github.com/Torfrancis447 | dev.to/torfrancis447

SUMMARY

A highly motivated and natural people-person software developer with experience designing and developing full stack applications as well as front-end applications. Experienced with front-end languages and libraries like Javascript and React as well as back-end languages like Ruby. Proven ability to provide excellent end-users experience with years of experience in sales and team-management.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, Javascript, React, HTML, CSS, Material UI, Bootstrap, SQL, PostgreSQL, Sqlite3, Git, Visual Studio Code, REST, API's

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Moodify - Github

An app for user's find music that matches your mood on spotify

- Front-end only project using HTML/CSS/vanilla JavaScript that accesses data from spotify API to guery playlists.
- Implemented toggleable CSS mode and In browser music player.

Gamer's Paradise - Github

An app where users can keep track of games they would like to play

- Created a react app using Bootstrap for the CSS and React Router for client-side routing.
- Utilized a frontend API to fetch Video game data to be able to search for games currently on the market

Dev Hunt - Github

A job board app for candidates looking for developer jobs and companies looking to hire talent

- A full stack application that follows RESTful API conventions and Active Storage for file uploading.
- Utilized a 3rd-party API to implement company interaction with job-seekers.

EXPERIENCE

Ainley's Search Group

Philadelphia, PA

Recruiter

06/2022 - 09/2022

- Consulted with clients to obtain a precise understanding of the technical job description and requirements to fill
 positions with high quality candidates in the manufacturing industry.
- Contributed to the acquisition of a major chemical Manufacturer.

Frank's Recruitment Group

Philadelphia, PA

Recruitment consultant

01/2022 - 05/2022

- Participate in business development to identify top accounts, target skill sets, and assess clients' ServiceNow needs.
- Negotiating employment offers for candidates in the ServiceNow industry.
- Exceeded expectation of placing a candidate with a client within 3 months starting.

Extra Space Storage District Team Lead

Philadelphia, PA

05/2016 - 01/2022

- Managed 7 different properties with up to 800 concurrent customers
- Lead team of 20 individuals to drive revenue and key performance indicators for a Fortune 500 company
- Exceeded expectation of property occupancy 4 years in a row and maintained occupancy rate of over 90% for 1 year.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School

Philadelphia, PA

Full Stack Web Development program

Rigorous coursework learning and applying the fundamentals of Javascript, React, SQL and Ruby on Rails.

10/ 2022 - 02/2023

Penn State University

Philadelphia, PA